How to make a prepaid or part payment for a home loan?
In this video, I am going to show you two methods with a demo, through
which you can easily make free payments or part payments for even the smallest and
largest amounts by simply visiting an online or offline
bank. I am going to
show you the whole thing with a demo, I am going to
show it live, so stay tuned in this video, I am going to
resolve all your queries
because many people had
commented and asked me how to make prepaid or
part payments. Is there any
benefit in doing so, and how much benefit is there for that?
You must watch this video
because it is a huge amount
when you keep taking out a home loan for 20-25 years. So, to
reduce it and
how to reduce it, I am going to show you the same thing in full detail in this video today.
Hello friends, my name is Girdhar.
Let's start the video. So friends,
as I told you, there are two methods here, I am going to
tell you about both these methods today, in
which the first one is online, in which
you can make the payment by submitting an application from any bank.
This payment can be of one EMI and
maximum up to five EMIs, but here different
banks provide this service in different ways,
but you will also have to
check whether your bank is allowing this thing
or not. Right now, let me take my
example here, I had taken a
home loan through ICC and here this bank
provides facilities where
I can make this payment online through its Android application, in
which my minimum payment will be of 1
EMI and maximum I can
pay up to six EMIs and I am going to show you this thing
with a live demo right now
and the second method in this is
very important because there will be many
people who want to make their payment or
their part payment, let us understand for example that
your home loan is of 20 lakhs
and you
want to pay 5 lakhs at once or
want to pay only 10 lakhs, then this is a very big
amount and what will you have to do in this case
because this  In the online method,
you will not be able to deposit such a large amount, so I will
tell you the complete process for that, and I will explain it step
by step, I will
explain it very clearly, but first of all, let's understand that this
third online method is there, many of my
brothers who want to make small investments
or make payments
with small amounts and want to take big benefits from it for a
long period, so
today I am going to tell you about that thing with a demo,
although I have an ICC Bank
application or I took a loan from it, so
I am going to tell you through this application, so
friends, first of all let's go to
my ICC Bank application, from
where I am not preferring the home loan ICC Bank
or I am
not promoting it, but this is a private
bank and I got a lot of good
feedback here, due to this
I got a lot of good feedback here
and because of this I took a home loan here
and my entire service till now has been
very good, so I am
logging in here, one good thing here is that the
online thing I am telling you about it is also
good, you will get the bank  You will never need to worry
because everything
is mostly done online and many banks
provide this support. You will
see here that when I logged in, the
loan field is shown separately.
I have a home loan running here, it is a
home loan of Rs 27,000. I had taken two separate loans. So,
if you click on the first home loan,
you will get all the details here
like the principal outstanding.
I have closed these loans, but here my
principal outstanding is zero.
How much did I take as a total loan? How much is my balance in the last few months?
And
how much is this for this particular loan. Now
inside this you will see, when you come under more options, the
first option you will see is pay
part payment. Now you have to
click on it. It depends on
different banks, Vijay, but
you will see all these things in whichever bank you
took the home loan from.
Look here, the first thing you will see is the loan
account number. This is very important for
whatever payment you are making. It is for your loan from your bank.  It
should be inside the account and not inside any other account.
Here you can see
how much amount is part payment on the inter amount, minimum one
EMI and maximum six EMIs. In this particular loan,
my EMI is Rs. 14000 and in the other one it is Rs.
13000. So here I do
not have to make minimum payment of Rs. 14000 and I can make
six times its maximum payment, that is, if you do it 6 times, then
I can make maximum payment of around Rs. 70000
in one go.
And here you can see the second option below,
what do you want to do with part payment, you
want to reduce your tenure, that is, you
want to reduce the balance in months, you want to reduce your EMI, you want to reduce the
EMI amount which
is Rs. 14000.
Generally you have to prefer 10 times, you should
never reduce the EMI. After this,
how will your debit happen, from where will the payment go, from
where will the money go inside the loan account, so
your account number should already be
popped here.  It must have been done, if
not then you will have to select it,
after this you have to click on I here Buy Agree and
go to the confirmation process, if
you do this then your full payment will be
directly credited to this loan account number,
generally it takes 48
hours to show you whether
your
outstanding amount of full payment i.e. principal amount has
reduced or not, but I found
one good thing in ICC here that as soon as
you make the payment,
your amount gets credited immediately in the principal account standing,
but bank to bank
defaults, as I told you,
this is a very simple method, I have
told you the first method
here, in which you can make payment from one EMI to
6 MI very easily online
sitting at home, but
for this you need to deposit money in your account,
now let's talk about the second method, in
which suppose you
want to deposit a big amount, say five lakhs, ten lakhs,
two lakhs, ten percent 20% payment  If you
want to deposit, what will you have to do in this condition?
In this condition,
you will have to visit the bank.
See, I have already done this entire thing and
I have deposited the money. For this, I am telling you the
entire step by step process
where you have to visit the bank and
you have to meet the loan authority or the loan area person. You have to meet
whichever officer is there
in the bank and
tell him that brother, I want to make a part payment. If you want to make a part
payment, then for that
you will definitely need two things, I will
tell you that also. The first thing is that the
part payment that you have to make will not be done in your account,
but you have to enter your loan account
number in the loan account number. So,
how can you make a part payment for that, there are
two ways. The first way is that what you should
do is take your cheque book
and for that, it is necessary to have enough money in your account.
These people do not accept the same in cash. I am
still telling you that when
we went for the first time, I
took the entire money in cash, but what will these people do?
First of all, take the cash.  You will get the cash
deposited in your account and
then you will have to give a cheque from the account and
in which account will you have to give that cheque,
you will have to mention your loan account number,
whatever your loan account number is, you will have to
mention it on the cheque and you will have to
tell how much you want to pay, suppose I want to pay
₹5 lakh, you will have to
sign this cheque and give this cheque
to the officer, as soon as you
give it to the officer, your cheque will be processed
and all your money will be deposited in this loan
account number, your
entire payment will be processed and this is
one method, now I just checked the second method
because when I was going to close, I had
some payment pending,
₹15000 and I had to close the bank, so when I
went there, I came to know that now
payment is also done through UPI, you have
money in any bank, that is, in another bank
and
you can deposit money directly in this loan account through UPI, so if
you go there, you can
also see this option  It is that
UPI code is actually generated there, a
new code is generated and given to you according to your loan
account number, then you have to
scan it and make the payment and through this
also your money gets deducted from the principal in your loan account number,
so this is what I have seen in ICC, it may be
that this thing may
not be available in other banks but
you will definitely find these two methods, first is this in
which you can make payment through Android app,
second is bank visit, if your
Android app does not support or there is
nothing in it then this method will definitely work
but you must pay attention to one thing here
that
how much amount is there for the payment, definitely check that the
bank is taking that much amount, generally in today's day no
bank charges any fee for the payment,
if your bank is
charging for the payment then my
request to you is that you divert or transfer your loan to such a bank
where there is no charge for all these payments, that's all
in this video, if  If
you liked the video then do give it a like
and also share it with your friends
who are trapped in this illusion or are
not able to understand anything. I will meet you
in some other new video. If you have any
doubt or query then do tell me in the comment box.
You will meet me in the next
video with some interesting content. Till then, tell this
Tanisted, goodbye and
Jai Hind.